<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Morgan's Blog</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog</link>
<description>Engineering deep dives, architecture notes, and backend lessons.</description>
<item>
<title>2017: When We Built the Future of Eyewear in Less Than a Second</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/polymagine-industry-4-eyewear-2017</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/polymagine-industry-4-eyewear-2017</guid>
<description>A retrospective on building biometric scanning, real-time 3D mesh generation, and AR/VR eyewear fitting in 2017.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quick feedback: ON CONFLICT DO UPDATE with nullable columns</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/postgresql-unique-nulls</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/postgresql-unique-nulls</guid>
<description>How to use NULLS NOT DISTINCT to make ON CONFLICT and unique indexes behave as expected with nullable columns.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Antigravity vs Cursor vs Claude Code: The Battle for the Developer&apos;s Soul</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/agent-battle-2026</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/agent-battle-2026</guid>
<description>A comparative analysis of developer AI agents through value, workflow impact, and infrastructure economics.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>From Smart to Sport: Why I Traded My Apple Watch for the COROS APEX 4</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/coros-apex-4</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/coros-apex-4</guid>
<description>A field review of endurance-watch tradeoffs for ultra trail training and race-day reliability.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Force Multiplier: AI as the New Engineering Substrate</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/ai-force-multiplier</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/ai-force-multiplier</guid>
<description>Why staff-level engineering shifts from raw implementation to orchestration when AI acceleration becomes ubiquitous.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Changing Hats: From Backend to Data Engineer at RockFi</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/backend-to-data-engineer-rockfi</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/backend-to-data-engineer-rockfi</guid>
<description>Why I transitioned towards Data Engineering at RockFi, diving into Dagster, medallion architecture, and our future with modern data warehouses.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Chapter: Joining RockFi as Staff Back-end Engineer</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/joining-rockfi</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/joining-rockfi</guid>
<description>Career update and technical mission context for building a scalable wealth-management platform.</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rebuilding Cloud Experience: The Trade-Offs of Serverless at Scale</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/rebuilding-cloud-experience-forest-admin</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/rebuilding-cloud-experience-forest-admin</guid>
<description>An incredibly deep dive into our journey transitioning from a self-hosted-only model to offering a Fully Hosted Cloud agent. We tackle Cold Starts, AWS Lambda Layers, VPC structuring, and why horizontal scaling is a database&apos;s worst enemy.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Escaping the Onboarding Matrix: Functional Factories to the Rescue</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/the-onboarding-matrix-forest-admin</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/the-onboarding-matrix-forest-admin</guid>
<description>A look back at our onboarding at Forest Admin, where supporting true self-hosted architectures forced us to build hundreds of separate setup flows, and how we solved it using functional factories.</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Idempotency and Debounce in BullMQ: hardening jobs with a jobify contract</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/idempotency-debounce-jobify-bullmq</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/idempotency-debounce-jobify-bullmq</guid>
<description>How to implement idempotent, debounced queue execution semantics with deterministic identifiers in BullMQ.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Node.js Backpressure for Massive History Exports: Streams, Async Generators, and S3 Multipart</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/nodejs-stream-backpressure-history-export</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/nodejs-stream-backpressure-history-export</guid>
<description>Production patterns for exporting massive historical datasets with bounded memory and resilient throughput.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jobify over BullMQ: a production pattern for jobs, workers, and queues (with NestJS)</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/jobify-workers-queues-nestjs</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/jobify-workers-queues-nestjs</guid>
<description>A production-ready queue orchestration pattern over BullMQ with stricter worker contracts and safer operations.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Breaking Through Firewalls: Why We Chose Server-Sent Events (SSE) for Agent Communication</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/architecture-sse-agent-communication</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/architecture-sse-agent-communication</guid>
<description>The architectural choices, joys, and sheer traumas of maintaining thousands of open HTTP connections across corporate firewalls.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>SCIM Provisioning: The Illusion of Standards and the Reality of RFC 7644</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/scim-user-provisioning-forest-admin</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/scim-user-provisioning-forest-admin</guid>
<description>How we implemented SCIM for user provisioning across Okta, Azure AD, and Google, while discovering that standard RFCs are more like loose guidelines.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Post-Mortem: The Day Redis Reached its Limits</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/redis-memory-exhaustion-post-mortem</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/redis-memory-exhaustion-post-mortem</guid>
<description>A weekend outage at Forest Admin caused by Redis memory exhaustion, highlighting the dangers of a single point of failure, data lifecycles, and scaling issues.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scaling CI at Forest Admin: When Tests Take Longer Than Your Lunch Break</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/scaling-ci-github-actions-forest-admin</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/scaling-ci-github-actions-forest-admin</guid>
<description>How we handled the explosion of CI times during our Series A scaling phase at Forest Admin, the nightmare of merging artifacts, and the endless pursuit of deterministic tests.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>When PostgreSQL Is No Longer Enough: Migrating Activity Logs to Elasticsearch</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/forest-admin-activity-logs-elasticsearch</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/forest-admin-activity-logs-elasticsearch</guid>
<description>How we navigated performance bottlenecks by migrating our massive activity logs system from PostgreSQL to Elasticsearch using a hybrid search architecture.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Security and authentication with identity federation (OpenID Connect)</title>
<link>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/security-authentication-idp-openid-connect</link>
<guid>https://thenkei.github.io/blog/en/posts/security-authentication-idp-openid-connect</guid>
<description>A production breakdown of OIDC, OAuth2 bearer tokens, and SAML assertion flows when one platform is both service provider and identity provider.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
